HITESH BHATIA

New Delhi, India

+91 9871983559

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hiteshbhatia3559

hiteshbhatia3559@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full time professional high frequency trader in the Indian Commodity and Currency market, with an in depth understanding and experience analyzing tick by tick data. Intensive experience in strategy and order execution analysis using large data sets in Python, and trading desks with turnover exceeding INR 500 crores per day.

Managing a portfolio of INR 30+ L part time, which is a combination of high frequency delta neutral arbitrage and spread strategies deployed to the cryptocurrency derivatives market, and medium frequency momentum trading using old school technical analysis.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

March 2019 - Present

IRAGE CAPITAL MUMBAI

Scrutinizing high frequency tick by tick data programmatically, and generating analysis and improvements for existing delta-1 strategies.

Traded a large variety of the Indian markets, primarily commodities (MCX) and Currencies (USDINR on NSE and BSE)

Developed Quality-of-life programs that automatically analyze data on a periodic basis, removing the need for manual analysis. Hands-on experience in Pandas for analysis and other libraries for data manipulation and transportation for automatic trade and data

DESIGNATED PARTNER

Nov' 2018 - March 2019

POINT FIVE CAPITAL NEW DELHI

Handled existing and onboarding new clients, raising INR 5M of

Developed manual profitable futures and options strategies Automated existing strategies, deployed to the Crypto market Closed due to regulatory issues

(still manging personal wealth on these strategies)

CYBER SECURITY ANALYST

June 2018 - Oct' 2018

ERNST & YOUNG LLP AEROCITY

Designed, wrote and deployed a Python based script called

Deployed to NIC-SOC, the center point of all government internet traffic in New Delhi

Designed and wrote a Thought Leadership around the Cryptocur-

rency space

EDUCATION

B. TECH - IT - 71%

NORTHERN INDIA ENGINEERING COLLEGE

Aug' 2014 - Aug' 2018

GGSIP University, New Delhi

CLASS 12TH BOARDS - 84%

March 2013 - March 2014

BAL BHARATI PUBLIC SCHOOL, NEW DELHI

OTHER INTERESTS

LEADERSHIP

Oct' 17 - Managed a team of 40 students and organized as the

Secretary General, Ouintessence Model UN, which is the largest free of cost Model UN conference held in India at Talkatora Indoor Stadium, in addition to eight other debates organized under Quintessence, the debating society of NIEC.

AWARDS

Over 50 awards and certificates in various capacities - adjudication, excellence in debate, organisation and participation with accolades for verbal communication, technical writing, teamwork and overall diplomancy

HOBBIES

Military flight simulation and army simulation gaming,

Graphic Designing (part time graphic designer for six years, with a large return on zero investment) Organized and hosted several Darknet and Cryptocur-

rency related seminars in the null community

PERSONAL PROJECTS

CROSS EXCHANGE HFT ARB WIP

Statistical leveraged arbitrage between two cryptocurrency derivatives exchanges Using Python (Redis, ccxt, websockets) Deployed to a Linux remote server 0.5ms tick latency, 0.8ms order execution time Seperate modules for data collection, risk controls, and quote based order sizing and strategy logic Orderbook resolution using orderbook deltas ROI - 3-4% per month, ROI to date - 53%

CALENDAR SPREAD HFT COMPLETED

High frequency calendar spread trading capturing backwardation and 3o contango. Predefined high/low threshold values with bollinger-band based extremity capture.

Similar network parameters and modules as above ROI - 11-15% per month, ROI to date 114%

TRADING SIGNALS COMPLETED

A comprehensive, three module indicator designed for manual medium frequency retail trading, hovering between 58% to 91% profitability per month depending on

volatility.

Developed as a Project in my Final Year, offered as a lifetime subscription based service.

-Per unit cost - Approximately 60 USD

-Number of sales - 250+ -Net profit - USD 15,000+

https://www.tradingview.com/script/MvqP3z3k-OneX-Hite-shB-Scalping-Indicator-1-0/

TECHNOLOGIES USED

PYTHON

One year of experience, intermediate level competency. Libraries used-Pandas, Matplotlib, ta-lib, ccxt, redis,

PINESCRIPT tradingview platform

Time series analysis, signals, alerts and indicators

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP

Six years of practical designing, with hundreds of logos and posters design for freelance sales

LINUX

Operational understanding of linux file systems, commands and basic awk scripting (aided with commandline python)

LINKS

TradingView: https://www.tradingview.com/u/hiteshbhatia 3559/#published-charts

GitHub: https://github.com/hiteshbhatia3559

Link to the design of this Resume -

https://github.com/hiteshbhatia3559/Resume